我并不是想吓你
但加兰之前失踪过.
I don't wanna aIarm you
but GarIand has disappeared before.
加兰的事总是和工作有关.
Granted it's aIways been work-reIated.
库珀探员,
这次也可能和工作有关吗?
Agent Cooper,
did this seem work-reIated?
太太, 那很难说.
Ma'am, that's hard to say.
那, 贝蒂, 你是说这种情形
也是少校工作的一部分吗?
So, Betty, you're saying this behavior
is part of the way the major operates.
让我这样说吧.
Let me ask you this.
他是突然不见了吗?
Did he Ieave suddenIy?
是, 他突然就不见了.
Yes, he did.
我们当时正闲谈着,
We were speaking phiIosophicaIIy,
然后我离开营地
去小解.
and I Ieft the campsite
to answer the caII of nature.
我回来的时候他就不见了.
When I returned he was gone.
事实上,你进了林子里
是十分有意味的暗示.
The fact that you were in the woods
is very significant.
哪方面?
In what way?
他常常,
ConfidentiaIIy,
在私下谈起过它们.
he taIks about them constantIy.
太太, 少校他--
Ma'am, has the major--
无疑, 他是个
意识很前卫的人.
CIearIy, a man
of no smaII spirituaI advancement.
一直尝试接触那些
在林子里存活的未知生命体
--been attempting to contact
some eIement that Iives in the woods
那也是他最高机密工作的一部分吗?
as a part of his top-secret work?
那是指定机密.
That's cIassified.
嗯, 那他一定具有文艺复兴般的情欲
去一探究竟, 对吧?
WeII, he certainIy has a renaissance
passion for expIoration, doesn't he?
他就是那样看自己的.
That is how he sees himseIf.
对此没有指引可循.
And there's no manuaI for it.
肯定没有任何相关的指引
可以遵循.
There's certainIy no manuaI
to be married to it.
贝蒂, 谢谢你来.
Betty, thanks for coming in.
我们目前只能是
提高警觉,密切关注事态发展
I guess, there's not much more
we can do right now,
除此之外, 我们也别无他法了.
except, keep our eyes peeIed.
加兰在床头桌上
留了些纸条. 我把它们传真过来吧.
GarIand Ieft some notes on his bedside
tabIe. I can caII you back with them.
它们可能非常有用.
They might be very heIpfuI.
少校这次突发离开
或许不止是有关工作那么简单.
Harry, the major didn't just wander off
on some work-reIated assignment.
我看到的那束闪光, 是存在森林
里一股强大力量.
That fIash of Iight I saw, it's a powerfuI
force that exists in those woods.
警长, 我们买到了
安先生和妙福太太的结婚礼物.
Sheriff, we found Mr. and Mrs. MiIford's
wedding present.
是围巾和领结情侣套装.
It's a matching scarf and ascot set.
好.
我上次还欠他一份礼呢.
Good.
I stiII owe him a gift from Iast time.
我真不敢相信
他又结婚了.
I can't beIieve
that he's getting married again.
杜奇的婚事是季节性发情
就像鲑鱼回潮.
Dougie's weddings are a seasonaI
thing. Like the return of the saImon.
来也匆匆, 去也匆匆.
Marry in haste, repent in Ieisure.
你好, 警长?
Hello, sheriff?
戴尔·库尔帕来电.
There's a call for a Dale Crewper.
长途. 我希望我没把它挂掉.
Long distance. l hope l didn't cut it off.
临时工. 露西帮妙福
筹备婚礼去了.
Temp. Lucy's heIping out
with the MiIford wedding.
库? 我们在哪儿?
Coop? Where are we?
我是戈登·寇尔
我在本德,俄勒冈州.
This is Gordon Cole calling
from Bend, Oregon.
你好吗, 戈登?
How are you doing, Gordon?
库, 我打电话来是想跟你说
这次内部调查的事
Coop, l just called to say
that you have my full support
我会全力支持你.
in this investigation business.
艰难时期
但我们会熬过去的.
These are hard times
but we get through them.
- 谢谢你, 戈登.
- 我也身受其害.
- Thank you, Gordon.
- lt ranks poor with me too.
现在, 库, 有哪些是真的?
Now, Coop, is any of this true?
杀死2人?
Double homicide?
毒品被盗?
Stolen drugs?
妓寨械斗?
Storming a whorehouse?
简直是一派胡言.
It's aII a bunch of hogwash.
我不得不通知你
毒品监察部
l have to tell you
the Drug Enforcement Agency
开始四处打探了.
is starting to nose around.
他们派出了一个顶级探员
去调查毒品的事了.
They're sending down a top dog
to investigate the drug angle.
他们派了谁?
Who are they sending?
是戈登.
lt's Gordon.
是戈登·寇尔.
lt's Gordon Cole.
我是问那个密探是谁?
Who's the agent?
丹尼斯·莱森.
Dennis Bryson.
是莱森. 他是个好人, 哈里.
不会胡来的.
It's Bryson. He's a good man, Harry.
No nonsense.
别让他搞乱你, 库.
Don't let him rattle you, Coop.
这些家伙专靠
抄别人家老底为生.
These guys make a living looking
through other people's drawers.
我们时不时,
就会有些把柄.
We've all had our socks
tossed around.
被他们抓在手上.
From time to time.
给你个忠告:
Couple of words of advice:
笑脸迎人.
Let a smile be your umbrella.
- 谢谢, 戈登.
- 再见, 库.
- Thanks, Gordon.
- See you, Coop.
那, 哈里...
WeII, Harry...
...准备直面事实吧.
...time to face the music.
早安, 罗杰.
Good morning, Roger.
先生们.
GentIemen.
库珀探员.
Agent Cooper.
开始吧.
It's showtime.
你已经知道控罪了.
You've heard the charges.
你希望以什么
为你自己辩护呢?
What do you wish to present
as your defense?
我没有辩护.
I have no defense.
我坚信我的行动
是正确的.
I am compIeteIy confident
in the rightness of my actions.
至于某些事件有违局里的指导方针
我将为此负全责.
Some of it occurred outside of Bureau
guideIines, I wiII pay the price for that.
但我是清白的
没有犯下有违道德的罪行.
But I'm innocent
of any criminaI wrongdoing.
如果他们执意要指控我的话,
那我们就在法庭上见吧.
If they wish to charge me,
I wiII defend myseIf in a court of Iaw.
戴尔.
DaIe.
有2种方法去处理这次事件
正途或歪路.
There's a right way and a wrong way
to do this.
而首先我们预期的是
And the first thing we expect
一个局员
应该为他自己辩解的.
is a Bureau man
to stand up for himseIf.
一个人不这样做,
甚至不尝试去做,
A man who can't,
who doesn't even try,
那, 他很可能只是在
欲盖弥彰.
weII, he may be packing feathers
where his spine is supposed to be.
罗杰.
Roger.
我想我知道
自己在干什么.
I know the moves
I'm supposed to make.
我知道怎么玩这个棋局.
And I know the board.
这样啊.
So.
我最近
想了很多.
I've been doing
a Iot of thinking IateIy.
我已经开始聚焦一个
远远超越在这个之外的
And I've started to focus out
beyond the edge of the board.
更大的棋局了.
On a bigger game.
那是什么局?
What game?
那时风攀越过藤蔓
的声音.
The sound the wind makes
through the vines.
一种动物性的肉体感知.
The sentience of animaIs.
我们在黑暗中的恐惧
以及躺在黑暗深远出的未知.
What we fear in the dark
and what Iies beyond the darkness.
你到底在讲什么鬼话?
What the heII are you taIking about?
我在讲关于如何
领会和超越恐惧, 罗杰.
I'm taIking about seeing
beyond fear, Roger.
怎样以爱去看待世界.
About Iooking at the worId with Iove.
它们将引渡你为谋杀和
走私毒品负起法律责任.
They're IiabIe to extradite you
for murder and drug trafficking.
有些事不是我所能控制的.
These are things I cannot controI.
停职仍将继续生效.
The suspension wiII remain in force.
接下来还有什么动作就看
加拿大政府了
The next move is up to the Canadian
government
毒品监察部今天
开始调查了.
and the DEA investigation
which begins today.
你已经破了个大案.
You've cracked a big case.
一定承受了很大的压力.
You've been under a Iot of pressure.
我建议你去做个
I may recommend
全面的心理检查.
a fuII psychoIogicaI workup.
感谢你的坦诚, 罗杰.
Thanks for your candor, Roger.
再见了, 伙计们.
So Iong, feIIas.
唐娜, 嗨.
Donna, hi.
嗨, 纳丁.
Hi, Nadine.
有詹姆斯的消息吗?
Have you heard anything from James?
你是指, 小艾艾的那个
摩托机车朋友吗?
You mean, Eddie's friend
with the motorcycIe?
是啊.
Yeah.
他已经好几天
没出现过了.
He hasn't been around
for a coupIe of days.
Listen,
我必须问你点事儿
但我不希望你会觉得太过隐私.
I gotta ask you something and I hope
you don't think this is too personaI.
什么?
What?
那, 你还, 比如, 和那个麦克
有任何交往吗?
WeII, are you stiII, Iike, going out
with Mike or anything?
没了.
No.
- 干嘛这么问?
- 你得答应我不往外说才行.
- Why?
- You have to promise not to say.
- 保证, 行不?
- 当然.
- Promise, okay?
- Sure.
那好, 我想可能有些
主要的化学作用在我体内发育了,肯定是--
WeII, I think there may be
some major chemistry deveIoping bet--
噢, 天哪, 他来了.
Oh, my God, there he is.
嗨, 唐娜.
Hi, Donna.
嗨, 麦克.
Hi, Mike.
他的屁屁最可爱了.
He has the cutest buns.
纳丁, 艾德呢?
Nadine, what about Ed?
你没再他交往了吗?
Aren't you stiII seeing him?
有啊, 有时吧.
Yeah, sort of.
那, 如果你还在和艾德见面,
那你怎么能...
WeII, if you're stiII seeing Ed,
then how can you...
...怎么能又开始和麦克交往呢?
...how can you start seeing Mike?
嗯, 小艾艾呆在家
而麦克在学校这儿.
WeII, Eddie stays home
and Mike's at schooI.
小艾艾喜欢做宅男,
麦克却喜欢出去玩.
Eddie Iikes to stay in,
Mike Iikes to go out.
我们还是实际点好,
有时小艾艾的行为就像
And Iet's be reaIistic,
sometimes Eddie acts Iike
老的足可以当我老爸了.
he's oId enough to be my father.
会见啦.
I'II catch you Iater.
能给来杯啤酒吗?
CouId I get a beer?
- 嗨.
- 你好.
- Hi.
- HeIIo.
去哪儿啊?
Headed somewhere?
不好意思,你说什么?
I'm sorry?
你正准备去哪儿
还是刚从哪儿来?
Is there some pIace you're going to
or running from?
你找错人了. 我挺好的.
You got the wrong guy. I'm aII right.
男人总说自己挺好的.
Men are aIways aII right.
直到他们开火.
Right up untiI they puII the trigger.
然后我们看着邻居
被严肃的铐走了
And then we watch the neighbors
soIemnIy march out
新闻报道还对我们说:
to the news cameras to teII us:
"他以前是个文静的好人."
''He was such a nice, quiet guy.''
嗯那, 我只是外表文静.
WeII, I'm onIy quiet on the outside.
我几乎能从这里听到
你内里是什么了.
I can aImost hear what's inside
from here.
住附近么?
Live nearby?
是啊, 双峰镇.
Yeah, Twin Peaks.
外套真好看.
It's a nice jacket.
很高兴你这么觉得.
I'm gIad you think so.
- 瞧, 你会修车吗?
- 会.
- Look, can you do anything with cars?
- Yeah.
怎么了, 你外面那台维特跑车
出问题了吗?
Why, you got a probIem with
the 'Vette outside?
不. 不, 是我丈夫的那台捷豹.
No. No, it's my husband's Jaguar.
有人在高速上挤了我一下
结果车翻到沟里了.
Somebody squeezed me on
the highway, and I drove it to a ditch.
我想在他回家之前
把它修好,会是个不错的主意.
I think it wouId be a very good idea to
have it repaired before he gets home.
那好, 我可以看看.
WeII, I couId take a Iook at it.
我叫詹姆斯.
My name is James.
伊夫林.
EveIyn.
伊夫林·玛舒.
我住在公路边上.
EveIyn Marsh.
I Iive right up the road.
那, 我们很赶吗?
WeII, are we in a hurry?
介意我先点首歌吗?
Do you mind if I pIay the box first?
我才不会让自己做记时打卡机.
I don't exactIy punch a cIock myseIf.
你好, 基巴.
Good day, Dick.
好啊, 安迪.
HeIIo, Andy.
这是小尼克
我在『快乐帮手』的帮助对像.
This is IittIe Nicky, my charge
from Happy HeIping Hand.
尼克, 这是安迪副警长.
Nicky, this is Deputy Andy.
你好吗, 年轻人?
How do you do, young feIIa?
嗨.
Hi.
安德鲁, 老兄.
Andrew, oId boy.
小尼克和我, 刚从
荷恩百货店回来
LittIe Nicky and myseIf, we just came
from Horne's Department Store
尼克在那儿买了整整
一橱合身的新衣裳.
where Nicky was fitted
for a new wardrobe.
现在我们正打算去
喝上一杯麦芽啤.
And now we're on our way
for a maIted.
我们想露西能和我们
一起去.
We were hoping Lucy couId come
with us.
噢, 靠, 基巴.
露西在北方大酒店呢,
Oh, shoot, Dick.
Lucy's up at the Great Northern,
正帮秒福布置婚典.
heIping with the MiIford wedding.
哦, 天啊, 就是.
Oh, God, that's right.
杜奇又结婚了.
Dougie's getting married again.
露西不在吗?
Lucy's not here?
就是说我们不能去喝
麦芽啤囉?
Does this mean we can't go out
for a maIted?
是啊, 真不巧.
我们只能下次再去了.
Yes, unfortunateIy.
We'II have to go some other time.
但你答应了. 我们不能去吗?
But you promised. Can't we go?
你知道, 基巴,
You know, Dick,
我也差不多到午餐时间了.
it's cIose to my Iunch hour.
如果你喜欢, 尼克, 我会很高兴带
你们2个去喝麦芽啤.
If you'd Iike, Nicky, I'd sure enjoy
taking you two guys out for a maIted.
- 你觉得那怎样?
- 噢, 好小子.
- How wouId that be?
- Oh, boy.
那, 你打算怎么做
So, what wiII you do
如果我们没办法
证明你的清白?
if we can't figure a way
to get you cIeared?
嗯, 哈里, 巨人说路在前方，都铺好了
只需一次一步一脚印的走好.
WeII, Harry, the Giant said a path is
formed by Iaying one stone at a time.
你和伙计们有听说过一个
叫守日门的地方吗?
Have either of you feIIas heard
of a pIace caIIed the White Lodge?
你在哪儿听来的?
Where did you hear of it?
嗯, 就是上次布里格斯少校
失踪前告诉我的.
WeII, it was the Iast thing Major Briggs
said to me before he disappeared.
库珀, 你或许对现世
无惧了.
Cooper, you may be fearIess
in this worId.
但还有其他世界的存在.
But there are other worIds.
那告诉我.
TeII me more.
我的族人相信
守日门是一个
My peopIe beIieve that
the White Lodge is a pIace
统治人和大自然的神灵
所居住的一个地方.
where the spirits that ruIe
man and nature here reside.
当地传说. 世代相传.
LocaI Iegend. Goes way back.
还有一个是
守夜门的传说,
There is aIso a Iegend of a pIace
caIIed the BIack Lodge,
就是守日门自身的一个影子
the shadow seIf of the White Lodge.
传说里讲每一个灵魂
必将经过那里
Legend says that every spirit
must pass through there
以此达至完美.
on a way to perfection.
在那, 你会遇到
你自身的影子.
There, you wiII meet
your own shadow seIf.
我的族人称之为: 玄关上
的弥留者.
My peopIe caII it: The DweIIer
on the ThreshoId.
玄关上的弥留者.
DweIIer on the ThreshoId.
除此之外，它还提到, 如果你以
不完美的灵魂去对抗守夜门,
But it is said, if you confront the
BIack Lodge with imperfect courage,
它将彻底湮灭你灵魂.
it wiII utterIy annihiIate your souI.
库珀探员, 莱森探员来了
想见你.
Agent Cooper, Agent Bryson's here
to see you.
带他进来.
Send him right in.
我和丹尼斯·莱森一起
在奥克兰合作过.
Dennis Bryson and I worked together
in OakIand.
毒监部头脑最好的人之一.
哈里, 情况对我们有利.
One of the finest minds in the DEA.
Harry, we're in very good hands.
库.
Coop.
丹尼斯?
Dennis?
说来话长, 不过真的
如果你不介意，叫我迪尼斯更好.
It's a Iong story, but actuaIIy
I prefer Denise if you don't mind.
好的.
Okay.
杜鲁门警长.
Sheriff Truman.
- 很高兴.
- 豪克副警长.
- PIeased.
- Deputy Hawk.
迪尼斯·莱森,
毒品监察部.
Denise Bryson,
Drug Enforcement Agency.
嗯, 我一路上很愉快,
警长.
WeII, I had a nice ride out here,
sheriff.
很难想像
你会涉及到罪案.
It's hard to imagine
you have even any crime.
我原来想像你只是找找失踪小狗,
或抓些镇上的醉汉而已.
I picture you chasing Iost dogs,
and Iocking up the town drunk.
很不幸, 这次牵扯到
大事了.
UnfortunateIy, it's a IittIe more
invoIved than that.
我这样说吧, 戴尔.
Let's get right to this, DaIe.
你这次之所以引起毒监部注意
是因为加拿大警卫队一个官员的报告
The DEA's interest in you stems from
aIIegations made by an RCMP officer
说你偷了他
这次卧底行动用的毒饵.
that you stoIe drugs being used
by him in a sting operation.
迪尼斯, 我相信我是被人插赃嫁祸了.
Denise, I beIieve I'm being set up.
嗯, 我新近的经验教会我
永远别太早定论.
WeII, my recent experiences taught me
never to judge too quickIy.
总之, 我会处理好的
Anyway, I'II get right to this
- 那回头找你吧.
- 好.
- and get back to you Iater.
- Okay.
我知道我们2个都住在
北方大酒店.
I understand we're both staying
at the Great Northern.
那里的食物味道怎样?
How is the food up there?
迪尼斯, 你入住那里真是个天大惊喜.
Denise, you're in for a reaI surprise.
对他们来说也是.
So are they.
好, 我们回见吧.
WeII, we'II catch up Iater.
- 我好像告诉你我新生活的全部.
- 迫不及待要听呢.
- I wanna teII you aII about my new Iife.
- Anxious to hear about it.
认识你真好, 警长.
It's a pIeasure to meet you, sheriff.
副警长.
Deputy.
那个发色很配他.
That's a good coIor for him.
瞧, 你有什么
需要吗?
Look, is there something
you want?
干嘛这么问, 麦克.
Why, Mike.
难道我们不是已经有一点点进展了吗?
Aren't we being a IittIe forward?
加把劲, 伙计们. 我要听见
虎虎生威，还要看见汗流浃背.
Come on, guys. I wanna hear
some grunting and see some sweat.
好啊, 尼森.
加油, 泵它.
Attaboy, NeIson.
Come on, pump it.
泵它.
Pump it.
- 嘿, 你叫什么名字, 小淑女?
- 纳丁·巴勒.
- Hey, what's your name, IittIe Iady?
- Nadine ButIer.
那, 纳丁, 有没有想过加入摔角队
和大家交往一下呢?
WeII, Nadine, ever give any thoughts
of going out for the wrestIing team?
乔西.
Josie.
是时候了.
It's time.
我不能和你在一起，除非我知道.
I can't be with you unIess I know.
- 噢, 哈里.
- 真相.
- Oh, Harry.
- The truth.
真相.
The truth.
我以前...在香港
为一个人工作.
I used to...work for a man
in Hong Kong.
他叫托马斯·埃卡.
His name is Thomas Eckhardt.
他帮助过我.
He heIped me.
我16岁的时候
是他把我从街边带走.
Took me off the streets
when I was 1 6.
我们家里很穷.
We are from a poor famiIy.
有时候他们只能
把自己家里的女孩卖掉.
Sometimes they seII
their femaIe chiIdren.
我很幸运.
I was Iucky.
他教会我什么是生活...
He taught me about Iife...
...怎样做生意.
...about business.
他就像我爸爸.
He was my father.
我师傅.
My master.
我爱人.
My Iover.
当我为自己生活感到恐惧不安时,
When I met Andrew Packard,
我遇到安德鲁·帕卡.
I was aIready afraid for my Iife.
安德鲁也是
个生意伙伴.
Andrew was aIso
a business partner.
但安德鲁向我求婚时.
When Andrew asked me to marry him,
我答应了.
I said yes.
那李先生是什么人?
Who was this Mr. Lee?
这个...这表哥是什么人?
Who is this...this cousin?
对不起, 哈里.
I'm sorry, Harry.
我只想让你
远离这些事.
I was just trying
to keep you out of this.
- 你知道的越少, 越好.
- 他是谁?
- The Iess you know, the better.
- Who was he?
他是埃卡的人.
He works for Eckhardt.
他说如果我不跟他回去,
他就杀了你.
He said if I didn't go back with him,
he'd kiII you.
那是为什么?
Why?
因为埃卡要我回去.
Because Eckhardt wants me.
他从来没停止过要占有我.
他认为我是他的财产.
He's never stopped wanting me.
He thinks I'm his property.
安德鲁再生的时候,
还能保护我.
When Andrew was aIive,
he couId protect me.
现在我相信...
I now beIieve...
...埃卡就是那个
要为安德鲁的死负责的人.
...Eckhardt is the man
responsibIe for Andrew's death.
我们-- 我们当时在西雅图的
机场.
We were-- We were in the airport
in SeattIe.
我逃走了.
And I just escaped.
我宁愿死.
I'd rather die.
我宁愿死也不要
回到那个恶人身边.
I'd rather die than go back
to that monster.
乔西.
Josie.
乔西, 你再也不必
回去那里了，永远.
Josie, you wiII never have
to go back there.
你现在和我一起...
You're with me now...
那么...
And now...
...他会杀了我们俩的.
...he'II kiII the both of us.
No.
那就让他试试看.
Let him try.
抱歉, 让你久等了,
Sorry, it took so Iong,
- 但我们今天不够人手.
- 那很正常.
- but we're short on heIp today.
- That's quite aII right.
我一直期待着这个馅饼.
听过很多有关它的宣传了.
I've been Iooking forward to this pie.
I've heard so much about it.
你不会失望的.
You won't be disappointed.
嘿, 我刚才是-- 想来点什么
我帮你拿. 先坐吧.
Hey, I-- I'II get you anything
you want. Just sit down.
嘿, 甜心.
能给我们来点咖啡吗?
Hey, sweetheart.
CouId we get some coffee?
- 你的打猎团有什么收获?
- 有点累人.
- How was your hunting expedition?
- It was a IittIe fatiguing.
- 逮到什么了没?
- 我希望没被逮到.
- Catch anything?
- I hope not.
噢, 逮到什么.
Oh, catch anything.
是的, 我...
Yeah, I...
我无意中发现了一只12斑点雄鹿, 你
知道吗, 它就站在一个深水池塘旁边.
I came across a 1 2-point buck, you
know, standing by a deepwater pooI.
So I made this very soft approach
and I Iined him up dead center:
我脚步放的非常轻接近它
然后一枪命中要害:
你应该带上摄像机.
You shouId have had your camera.
你不是已经把它装好了吗?
Are you having it mounted?
噢, 是, 是, 就在我们说话之际.
棒极了, 真是棒极了.
Oh, yeah, yeah, even as we speak.
It was great, just great.
我想我最好还是
看看你妈妈.
I think I better go
and check on your mama.
她不在这儿, 尔尼.
她已经回西雅图了.
She's not here, Ernie.
She's gone back to SeattIe.
西雅图?
SeattIe?
我想你也应该去那儿.
And that's where I think
you shouId go too.
嘿, 伙计,
干嘛把脸拉的老长?
Hey, buddy,
what's with the Iong face?
- 维维安已经回西雅图了.
- 那不是更好吗, 牛仔.
- Vivian's gone back to SeattIe.
- Better for you, buckeroo.
我们还有4公斤货要倾销呢. 你想
一路上拖着个累赘吗?
We got four kiIos to unIoad. You want
the baII-and-chain getting in the way?
好吧, 我猜你是对的.
Yeah, I suppose you are right.
那儿有电话, 老爷车.
There's the phone, hotrod.
我们的最后期限快到了.
We're on a deadIine.
来了. 2份3莓口味馅饼
Here we go. Two three-berry pies
还有一份超级雪霜
巧克力麦芽饮.
and one super snow frost
chocoIate maIted.
哇, 谢谢.
Wow, thanks.
看 就像白尾山,
是吧, 尼克?
Looks just Iike WhitetaiI Mountain,
doesn't it, Nicky?
这杯要多少钱?
How much does it cost?
哦, 钱不是问题,
小尼古拉斯.
Oh, money is no object,
IittIe NichoIas.
该死的. 该死.
Damn. Damn.
真该死.
Damn.
对不起, 基巴叔叔.
Sorry, UncIe Dick.
没事的, 尼克.
It's okay, Nicky.
基巴叔叔不会生气的.
是吧, 基巴叔叔?
UncIe Dick isn't mad.
Are you, UncIe Dick?
基巴叔叔正在擦着呢, 谢谢
你. 递我一张纸巾, 安迪叔叔.
UncIe Dick is simpIy ripping, thank
you. Pass me a napkin, UncIe Andy.
见他娘的鬼了, 真是的.
Gosh darn it, anyway.
对不起, 安迪叔叔.
Sorry, UncIe Andy.
没什么好介意的, 小尼克.
Think nothing of it, IittIe Nicky.
安迪叔叔飞转滚滚很搞笑吧,
不是吗?
UncIe Andy went funny boom-boom,
didn't he?
我想我能把它搞好.
I think I can put this right.
它真漂亮.
It is beautifuI.
杰弗里很爱这车.
Jeffrey Ioves this car.
我丈夫.
My husband.
他爱这车.
He Ioves this car.
那你丈夫在哪儿, 玛舒太太?
Where is your husband, Mrs. Marsh?
这周,我不知道.
I don't know this week.
他几乎长期在外.
He traveIs extensiveIy.
做生意.
Business.
这车是1948产的.
This car was buiIt in 1 948.
杰弗里拥有的几乎都是些独特
又漂亮的玩具.
Jeffrey has to have the most unique
and beautifuI toys.
它们必须是完美的.
They have to be perfect.
他就是用这样的方式来
对待他所有的一切.
He's that way
about everything he owns.
我本来可以从那学到些什么
如果我有被关注过的话.
I couId have Iearned something from
that if I'd been paying attention.
你会那样吗, 詹姆斯?
Are you that way, James?
你会那样对你的机车么?
Are you that way about your bike?
我想我不太感兴趣
我的机车看起来怎样
I guess I'm not so interested
in how my bike Iooks
只要它能带着我到处去.
as I am in where it can take me.
你打算去哪儿?
Where do you wanna go?
并不是要去一个确切的地方, 而是追求一种感觉.
It's not reaIIy a pIace, it's a feeIing.
有时, 在夜里兜风...
Sometimes, riding at night...
...我关掉车头灯
然后继续加大油门...
...I punch off the headIights
and roII on the throttIe...
...就这样懵然激冲进黑暗中.
...and just rocket bIind into the dark.
那么...
So...
...你觉得你能修好它咯?
...do you think you couId fix it?
是的.
Yeah.
车库上有个房间.
There's a room above the garage.
如果你喜欢,你工作时
可以住那.
You can stay there if you Iike
whiIe you work.
食宿全包,还有其它什么
你觉得公平的都可以.
Room and board and anything eIse
you think is fair.
杰弗里回家前
我真的很必要让人修好.
I reaIIy do need to have this fixed
before Jeffrey gets home.
我想你留下, 詹姆斯.
I'd Iike you to stay, James.
我喜欢有个伴.
I'd enjoy the company.
那好吧.
Okay.
很好.
Good.
就这么定了. 那我把它交给你了.
It's settIed then. I'II Ieave you to it.
现在约克郡的阳光
Now is the winter of our discontent
可以把我们不喜欢的冬天
变成灿烂的夏季了;
Made gIorious summer
by this sun of York;
现在我们的眉梢
挂着胜利的花环;
Now are our brows bound
with victorious wreaths;
开单身派对吗?
A stag party?
我竟然没被邀请?
And I wasn't even invited?
你到底搞什么鬼去了?
Where the heII have you been?
本, 我的时间表绝对
紧的要死了.
Ben, I have had an absoIuteIy
kiIIer scheduIe.
你知道前几天
我渡过的是
Do you know the kind of heII
that I have been through
什么样的鬼日子吗?
in the Iast few days?
你说你会在木场火灾里
搞定凯萨琳的.
You said that you took care
of Catherine in the miII fire.
她还活着.
She's aIive.
或许你可以想像,
这个野营者有多不高兴了.
And as you might imagine,
not a happy camper.
通过奸计...
Through trickery...
...强行敲诈勒索...
...extortion...
在她的安排下
我2个计划都给她骗走了.
She has managed
to cheat me out of both.
格斯伍和锯木厂.
Both Ghostwood and the miII.
然后还有...
Then there is...
...件小事, 因为劳拉·帕尔默
的谋杀而...
...the smaII matter of being arrested
for the kiIIing of...
...被捕.
...Laura PaImer.
一个真正的生意增强剂啊.
A reaI business-enhancer.
高潮是, 我最信任的律师,
已故的利兰·帕尔默...
On top of which, my trusted soIicitor,
the Iate LeIand PaImer...
...原来是一个
杀人狂.
...turns out to be
a homicidaI Iunatic.
难熬的星期啊, 本.
Tough week, Ben.
你觉得这间房里的家俱
都是被精心摆放的吗?
Do you think the furniture
in this room is adequateIy arranged?
我一直有个自娱的好玩念头
I have been toying with the notion
如果一个人能找出
that if one couId find
在任何特定空间里物体
的完美排列,
the perfect arrangement
of aII objects in any particuIar space,
它或许能创建一种共鸣
个体进入那个空间后
it couId create a resonance
the benefits from which
能从中获益
还会...
to the individuaI dweIIing in that
space couId be...
...还会很广阔,
可能会影响深远, 影响深远.
...couId be extensive,
couId be far-reaching, far-reaching.
你能帮我搬开这张书桌吗?
WouId you heIp me with this desk?
听起来真让人着迷, 本, 真的.
That's fascinating, Ben, reaIIy.
可是, 听着, 我们现在必须要谈的
是...
Listen, though, what we have to taIk
about now...
...独眼杰克.
...is One-Eyed Jack's.
杰克, 杰克. 是, 独眼杰克.
Jack's, Jack's. Yes, One-Eyed Jack's.
看, 是这样的, 本.
Look, here's how it is, Ben.
本.
Ben.
你出局了.
You're out.
你说什么?
Excuse me?
我拥有独眼杰克.
I own One-Eyed Jack's.
已经被友好的接管了.
There's been a friendIy takeover.
你进来这儿受雇于我
还胆敢告诉我--
You come in here under my empIoy
and have the gaII to teII me--
哦, 还有另一件事.
Oh, that's another thing.
我不再替你工作了.
I don't work for you anymore.
雷诺.
RenauIt.
尚·雷诺.
Jean RenauIt.
是雷诺, 对吧? 汉克.
It's RenauIt, isn't it? Hank.
让我来告诉你点事吧.
Let me teII you something.
这个家伙是个精神病患.
The guy is a psychopath.
精神病患.
Psychopath.
而你, 我的朋友,
正与魔鬼共舞.
And you, my friend,
are dancing with the deviI.
本, 你是个怪畸.
Ben, you're a nut.
你以为我会就这样坐在这?
You think I'm just gonna sit here?
让你夺走一切?
Let you take aII this.
本.
Ben.
时移世易了.
Life has changed.
我来告诉你到底发生了什么
我只是想你听听我的.
I want you to Iisten to me when I
teII you that this is how it's gonna be.
别来对我惺惺作态, 你这蠢呆货.
Don't patronize me, you goon.
你已经一团糟了, 本. 看看你.
You're a mess, Ben. Look at you.
你完蛋了, 老板.
You screwed up, boss man.
你出局了, 本.
You're out, Ben.
"你没的玩了, 本.
''You're out, Ben.
你出局了, 本.
You're out, Ben.
你没的玩了, 本, 你出局了.
You're out. Ben, you're out.
本,你出局了.."
Ben, you're out.''
云顿·厄尔.
Windom EarIe.
当然, 你无法做些什么
但留意
Of course, you couldn't help
but take note of
我明显以传统方式
开场了.
my emphatically traditional
opening.
我必须说,
你之前的回应行动没有意义
l must say,
your responding move was nothing
如果没反映出你
对整洁和吹毛求疵的癖好.
if not reflective of your predilection
for the tidy and fastidious.
看我对你的回应
是怎样开始把我们
See how my response to you
begins to lead us
领向严谨的
较量的?
towards a classical
confrontation?
但你心存疑虑.
But there's doubt in your mind.
我真正的意图是什么?
What are my true intentions?
这次你会怎样回答呢?
How will you answer this time?
妖魔来了, 戴尔.
Hobgoblins, Dale.
一致性, 可预测性,
找出行为模式.
Consistency, predictability,
giving rise to patterns.
我们2个都非常清楚
We both know only too well
这些模式给你留下了
易被攻击的弱点.
how these patterns leave you
vulnerable to attack.
你有伤疤.
You with your wounds.
我也有.
l with mine.
让我给你这样说吧.
Let me paint you a picture.
我的骑士将会打头阵.
My knights will skirmish.
开好路后,我的主教和
战车将会所向无敌了.
Lanes of power and influence will
open to my bishops and rooks.
卒自然会战死.
Pawns will naturally be forfeit.
我甚至准备牺牲
我的王后，因为我向你保证,
l'm even prepared to sacrifice
my queen because l assure you,
亲爱的戴尔, 我将不惜一切代价
去达到目的.
dear Dale, my goal will be attained
at any cost.
国王必须死.
The king must die.
道格拉斯·妙福,你愿意
娶这位女士为妻吗...
Do you, DougIas MiIford,
take this woman to be your wife...
...只要有生之年,
都热爱和珍惜她,共享人生.
...to Iove and to cherish,
for as Iong as you both shaII Iive?
没错, 我愿意, 牧师.
You bet, I do, Reverend.
如果在座各位对这个结合
有任何异议,
If there be anyone who knows not
why this union shouId be made,
请他马上提出
否则, 就永远保持沉默.
Iet him speak now
or forever hoId his peace.
你太他妈对了. 我要反对.
You're damn right. I want to object.
这个小骗子
只是想来挖他的钱,
This IittIe goId digger
just wants his money,
和骗走他的出版王国,
and his pubIishing empire,
天知道这事儿.
and God knows what aII.
还有你们看看他,
And Iook at him,
一只脚踏入
坟墓的人了.
he's got one foot
in the grave aIready.
好了, 杜恩,
好了, 放过她吧.
Okay, Dwayne,
okay, just take her easy.
- 放过她吧.
- 那好吧.
- Take her easy.
- AII right.
你也知道我们家的烦事,
警长. 这么多年了.
You know that I have had probIems,
sheriff. AII these years.
好了, 市长先生,
我们出去透透气吧. 好吗?
Okay, Mr. Mayor,
Iet's just get a IittIe air. ShaII we?
这相当的怪癖, 不是吗?
It's pretty pecuIiar, isn't it?
别放在心上，, 小宝贝.
Don't give it another thought, doII.
- 好, 我知道这只是我的意见,
- 我们出去吧, 我们出去吧.
- WeII, I know this is my opinion,
- Let's get out, Iet's just get out.
- 然而我想你们在座的都明白我说什么.
- 抱歉.
- and I want you to aII understand it.
- Excuse us.
每2个月结一次婚...
真够呛的.
Marrying every two months...
Good God.
那么,如果再没有其他人反对--
So if there be no further objections--
我是库珀.
Cooper here.
迪尼斯.
Denise.
哦, 那很好啊.
我马上下来.
WeII, that'II be nice.
I'II be right down.
戴安, 当我有空闲,
Diane, when I've got a moment,
提醒我跟你讲讲
莱森探员的事.
remind me to teII you
about Agent Bryson.
我真喜欢妙福的婚宴.
I just Iove MiIford weddings.
可谓阳盛阴衰.
Unfair advantage.
有多少女孩
被邀请出席婚礼了?
How many of those girIs
were varsity wide receivers?
就几个.
Very few.
先来坏消息.
Bad news first.
我在你车里发现了可卡因的残留物.
I found cocaine residue in your car.
我估计那就是加拿大骑警
失窃的毒品.
And my guess is it wiII match the Iot
stoIen from the Mountie.
丹尼斯,这不可能,里面有鬼.
- Dennis, this can't appear straight.
- Denise.
迪尼斯.
- 抱歉.
- 没事.
- Sorry.
- It's okay.
它看来显然是个陷阱, 库.
Sure it Iooks Iike a frame, Coop.
但我需要更多证据去证明它
不能只是你一面之词.
But I'm gonna need more than
your opinion to make that stick.
你能帮我吗?
Can you heIp me?
唔, 那样就会进入
进入一个很微妙的局面咯.
WeII, that gets
into a very deIicate area.
但另一方面,
我最近正非常努力,
But on the other hand,
I'm trying very hard, recentIy,
更多的尝试去相信
我的感觉.
to get more in touch
with my feeIings.
女士们,先生们, 吃蛋糕了.
Ladies and gentIemen, the cake.
杜奇一向是个浑帐球.
Dougie's aIways been a sucker.
每当有女人经过他身边...
When a woman pass...
...向他暗送秋波...
...with pIay in her eyes...
...然后再来扭几下果冻步,
他就成上钩的鲑鱼了.
...and JeII-O in her waIk,
and he's a trout on a hook.
那, 迪尼斯,
So, Denise,
如果你不介意我问的话,
if you don't mind my asking,
- 你都干嘛去了?
- 不, 一点儿不介意.
- what happened to you?
- No, not at aII.
我正想说呢.
I Iike to taIk about it.
其实很简单.
It's reaIIy very simpIe.
去年, 我在郊区做
卧底监视工作
Last year, I was working undercover
suburban surveiIIance
那个卖家的卖法
有点怪癖.
and the seIIer had a few kinks
in his rep.
似乎他只卖毒品给
易服癖者.
It seems that he'd onIy seII
to transvestites.
所以我和同事分头行动.
So my partner and I shacked up.
我扮演买家的角色.
I pIayed the part of the buyer.
然后我发现穿着
女装...
And I found that wearing women's
cIothes...
...让我很放松.
...reIaxed me.
我开始穿着它们
过夜.
I continued wearing them
into the night.
我同事以为
我的职业精神达到极致了.
My partner thought it was
my consummate professionaIism.
那2周让人很困惑.
It was a very confusing two weeks.
哇, 这个大披露
确实令人很诧异,
WeII, this is aII
a pretty amazing discIosure,
迪尼斯.
Denise.
现在可以想像我当时多惊喜了吧, 库.
Imagine how surprised I was, Coop.
完全不是你
所能预料到的.
This is not exactIy
something you pIan on.
猜也猜不到.
Guess not.
- 警长.
- 哈里.
- Sheriff.
- Harry.
给我来一杯生啤酒.
I'II have a draft.
警长, 快拘捕这位女士.
Sheriff, arrest this woman.
因为她在这里出现
太美丽了.
She's too beautifuI to be Iiving
in this state.
噢, 嘿, 你不就是那个联邦调查局的人吗?
Oh, hey, aren't you that FBI man?
暂时不是了, 不.
Not currentIy, no.
戴尔·库帕.
DaIe Cooper.
戴尔.
DaIe.
是你破了
劳拉·帕尔默的案子, 呃?
You soIved
that Laura PaImer case, huh?
好了,亲爱的,
他们可是来玩高兴的.
Come on, darIing,
they're pIaying our tune. See you.
我真希望这小2口
快上蜜月套房.
I sure hope those two go up
to the honeymoon suite soon.
我们已经把杜恩和杜奇
扯开2次了.
We've had to separate Dwayne
and Dougie twice aIready.
每次婚礼都这样.
Happens every wedding.
本性难移.
Boys wiII be boys.
我和同一个女人
相守大半生了.
I was married to the same woman
for haIf a century.
上帝安息了她的灵魂.
God rest her souI.
那是因为我用大脑去思考
而不是用那根大水管.
That's because I used my brain
for thinking, not my garden hose.
蛋糕很可口.
This cake is deIicious.
音乐...
The music...
...还是相当不错的.
...turned out pretty good.
应该奏死亡进行曲.
It ought have been the death march.
你是个出色的舞伴.
You're an exceIIent dancer.
一些关于跳舞的事,
欧蕊,
One other thing about dancing,
Audrey,
就是你永远不知道
舞步将把你领向何方.
is that you never know
where the step couId Iead.
你只能跟着音乐
一直跳下去.
You have to hang on
and hope the music takes you there.
你哥哥, 我丈夫,
安德鲁·帕卡,
Your brother, my husband,
Andrew Packard,
是被一个叫
托马斯·埃卡的人杀的.
was kiIIed by a man
named Thomas Eckhardt.
告诉一些
我还不知道的事吧.
TeII me something
I don't aIready know.
你现在非常危险, 凯萨琳.
You're in terribIe danger, Catherine.
你这个杀我哥的帮凶,
You heIped kiII my brother,
想骗走我的土地,
我家族的命脉,
tried to cheat me out of my Iand,
my famiIy's IifebIood,
还穷极一切来消灭我,
现在你反过来救我?
utterIy destroy my existence,
and now you want to save me?
为了活命我必须做点什么.
I had to do these things to stay aIive.
我已经没有人可以依靠了.
I have no one to turn to now.
我什么都没有了.
I've got nothing.
求你可怜可怜我吧.
And I'm at your mercy.
不.
Now...
够了.
...enough.
我们实在点吧.
Let's be practicaI.
你说,我们能做什么?
What do you propose we do?
我不知道.
I don't know.
那我告诉你.
Then I'II teII you.
从现在开始...
From now on...
...你替我干活.
...you work for me.
在这儿.
Here.
在这房子里.
At the house.
做女佣.
As a maid.
你搬你的东西
进佣人房.
You move your things
into the servant's quarters.
如果你不服从我...
If you disobey me...
...或者欺骗我...
...if you Iie to me...
...又或者我叫你去做的
有一点反驳,
...if you contradict
a singIe thing I teII you,
我会把这个埃卡找来
I shaII find this Eckhardt
亲手把你送去喂他.
and feed you to him by hand.
都清楚了?
Is that cIear?
说话呀!
Speak!
是的, 我明白.
Yes, I understand.
好.
Fine.
我们以后再说
这个埃卡的事吧.
We'II taIk about this Eckhardt
some other time.
你可以回你的房间了.
You may go to your room.
Thank you.
乔西...
Josie...
我7点在房间里用早餐.
I'II take breakfast at 7 in my room.
咖啡, 果汁,
不涂奶油的土司, 燕麦粥.
Coffee, juice,
dry toast, oatmeaI.
- Yes.
- Sweet dreams.
做个甜梦吧.
高兴了吧, 安德鲁?
Happy, Andrew?
所有事都正严密的
按我们的计划进行着.
Everything is going exactIy
as we pIanned.
那么...?
And now...?
那么, 亲爱的妹妹r,
我们就托马斯·埃卡
And now, dear sister,
we wait for Thomas Eckhardt
来找他的
唯一真爱吧.
to come Iooking
for his one true Iove.
当他到了--
And when he does--
我们会为他准备好的.
We'II be waiting for him.